[
    {
        "question": "What are variables in Python used for?",
        "answer": "Data"
    },
    {
        "question": "What determines the scope of a variable?",
        "answer": "Location"
    },
    {
        "question": "Can a variable inside a function be accessed outside of it?",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of variable is accessible throughout the script?",
        "answer": "Global"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of variable is local to a function?",
        "answer": "Local"
    },
    {
        "question": "What concept ensures variables have the correct data type?",
        "answer": "Type hinting"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are lists in Python mutable?",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are strings in Python mutable?",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of variable is created when a string is modified?",
        "answer": "New"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is Python statically typed?",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main advantage of Pythonâ€™s dynamic typing?",
        "answer": "Flexibility"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are variables declared explicitly in Python?",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "Can global variables be accessed inside a function?",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is mutable data type changeable?",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are variable types checked at runtime in Python?",
        "answer": "Yes"
    }
]
